Hello, everybody.
Welcome back to the IELTS Intermediate Speaking Course by PREP.
In the previous lesson, we learned the FER technique to expand our answers in IELTS speaking.
They are feeling, example, and reason.
Today, we'll add one more item to further extend your answer.
Explanation.
So, FER now becomes FEER, feeling, example, explanation, and reason.
Let me give you an example.
I have a question as follows.
What kind of people do you like to have as friends?
And this is my answer.
When it comes to people I prefer to have as friends, several qualities are important to me.
For one, I appreciate individuals who are trustworthy and fiercely loyal, who
I can confide in and never use my secrets against me.
Secondly, I value friends who can be brutally honest and tell me
what I need to hear about my flaws to improve myself.
As you can see, I further explained about these several qualities, trustworthy and fiercely loyal, brutally honest.
And for each of these qualities, I explained how they are expressed.
When it comes to people I prefer to have as friends, several qualities are vital to me.
For one, I appreciate individuals who are trustworthy and fiercely loyal, who
I can confide in and never use my secrets against me.
Secondly, I value friends who can be brutally honest and tell me
what I need to hear about my flaws to improve myself.
Now, I'll be in the role of both the examiner and the candidate to provide sample answers.
After each sample answer, please read the sample on screen out loud.
Let's begin.
Do you have many close friends?
No, I don't.
The reason is, as an introvert, I have quite a narrow circle
of close friends, and I am lucky enough to have a few
individuals I can always turn to for help and support whenever life gets rough.
Example.
Actually, I only have two incredibly close buddies within my social circle.
We went way back to our school days, and since then, they
have consistently stood by me through all ups and downs of my
life, when I broke up with my girlfriend or lost my job during COVID pandemic.
Do you think friendship is important?
Yes, it is.
In my opinion, friendship is indispensable in our life.
Reason.
In the face of life's inevitable challenges, we always need someone to support us through all the difficulties.
Example.
Like a shoulder to cry on whenever we feel down.
Feeling.
It is a wonderful feeling to know there are always people who
will go out of their ways to lend you a helping hand when life gets rough.
What kind of people do you like to have as friends?
When it comes to people, I prefer to have as friends.
Several qualities are vital to me.
Explanation.
For one, I appreciate individuals who are trustworthy and fiercely loyal, who
I can confide in and never use my secrets against me.
Secondly, I value friends who can be brutally honest and tell me
what I need to hear about my flaws to improve myself.
Now let's apply the FEER technique in some sample part three questions.
The first question is, is it important for celebrities to be good role models?
For this question, my answer is, yes, I definitely believe they have
a moral obligation to act responsibly, given their massive influence.
My reason is, this is because young people often idolize public figures
and tend to mimic their behaviors, whether those actions are positive or negative.
I will also provide an example for further information.
For instance, when a famous athlete promotes a healthy lifestyle or charity
work, it can inspire millions of fans to do the same.
Next question, how has technology changed the way we spend our free time?
My answer is, it's clear that technology has shifted our leisure activities
from being active and social to more sedentary.
The explanation is the convenience of digital entertainment.
We no longer need to leave our homes to be entertained.
And an example for this is, a decade ago, people might have
gone to the cinema to see a movie, but now most of
us prefer streaming services like Netflix on our tablets.
Last question, do you think people will rely more on robots in the future?
First, I give my answer that I believe that our reliance on
automation will increase significantly in the coming years.
And then I will extend my answer by sharing my feeling about
this as I feel quite positive about this because I think robots
can make our lives much easier and safer.
Great job everyone.
Today, we learned a new technique to brainstorm ideas and extend answers in Speaking Part 3.
Now let's review what we learned through some exercises.
We upgraded the FER technique by adding another E, explanation.
Don't forget to review this lesson, finish all the exercises, and practice
more at home to be confident in the exam room.
Till next time everybody.
Bye-bye.